Guide to the Carolina Wren Press Records, 1940-1994, undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Carolina Wren Press records 1940-1994 and undated
Carolina Wren Press
80 linear feet Extent: 117,750 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00198
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is partially restricted.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Carolina Wren Press Records, 1940-1994 and undated, were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1994.
Biographical Note
1937 May 27 Judith Ann Stevenson born in Hutchinson, Kansas
1959 B.A., University of Oklahoma
1959-1960 Attended graduate school at University of Indiana
1960 Married Thomas Fordham
1964 Obtained divorce from Thomas Fordham
1964-1968 Attended University of California at Berkeley
1967 Married Terry Hogan
1969 Founding of Lollipop Power Press
1969-1981 Judy Hogan served as editor of Hyperion
1971 Judy Hogan moved to Durham, N.C.
1975-1976 Judy Hogan chaired the national small press grassroots organization Committee of Small Magazine Editors and Publishers (COSMEP)
1975 Judy Hogan taught writing classes, including "A Roadmap for Great Literature for New Writers"
1976 Obtained divorce from Terry Hogan
1976 Judy Hogan founded Carolina Wren Press
1978 Home Grown Books project
1978 Carolina Wren Press, Inc. became a non-profit tax-exempt organization
1982-1983 Judy Hogan served as Writer in Residence at the Durham Library
1985 Carolina Wren Press became a funded affiliate of the Durham Arts Council
Collection Overview
The Carolina Wren Press Records span the years 1940 through 1992, with most of the material dated between 1970 and 1990. The papers are divided into two large groups, the Carolina Wren Press Records and the Carolina Wren Press Records: Judy Hogan Papers.
The Carolina Wren Press Records group contains material relating to the founding and publishing activities of the press and to organizations with which the press was affiliated. The papers are divided into the following series: Correspondence, Writings, Publications, Printed Material, Lollipop Power Press (a feminist press publishing non-sexist children's books), Homegrown Books (a publication for reviews of small press work), Hyperion (a poetry journal), Grant Material, Organizations, Office Files, Financial Papers, COSMEP (Committee of Small Magazine Editors and Publishers), and Photographs and Audiovisual Material. Each of these series documents not only the growth and activities of Carolina Wren Press and associated organizations, but also the origins and development of the small press movement in the United States and particularly in the South.
The Carolina Wren Press Records: Judy Hogan Papers group documents the life and activities of the author Judy Hogan, the founder of Carolina Wren Press. The material is divided into the following series: Correspondence, Diaries, Writings, Teaching Materials, Financial Papers, Biographical Material. While some of the correspondence and diary entries may mention the Carolina Wren Press, the papers in this group focus primarily on Hogan's personal life, her education, her writing and projects, and her teaching activities.
Subject Headings
Carolina Wren Press; Hogan, Judy, 1937-; Lollipop Power; Committee of Small Magazine Editors and Publishers; Homegrown Books; Hyperion; Publishers and publishing -- North Carolina; Little presses -- North Carolina; Women publishers -- North Carolina; Little presses -- Southern States; Authors, American -- Southern States; Creative writing -- Study and teaching; Diaries
Contents of Collection
- Carolina Wren Press Records Series
  - Correspondence Subseries, 1971-1992 and undated
    Correspondence concerning the management of Carolina Wren Press and its publications. Arranged chronologically by month and year.
    - 1971-1987 (Box 1)
      (Restricted)
    - 1988-1992 and undated (Box 2)
  - Writings Subseries, 1972-1990 and undated
    Chiefly literary manuscripts (some photocopies), including novels, poetry, essays, and stories submitted for publication by Carolina Wren Press.
    Arranged alphabetically by authors name.
    - Achuman, Mark (Box 3)
    - Adams, Hadie (Box 3)
    - Aiken, Conrad (Box 3)
    - Akinwole, Barbara S. (Box 3)
    - Allen, Emily (Box 3)
    - Allen, Jo Harvey (Box 3)
    - Altman, W. Forrest (Box 3)
    - Ananicz, Frank (Box 3)
    - Anders, Shirley B. (Box 3)
    - Anderson, Maggie (Box 3)
    - Andrus, Clayton E. (Box 3)
    - Angeli, Mary-Louise (Box 3)
    - Applegarth, Margaret (Box 3)
    - Ascher, Randee R., (6 folders) (Box 3)
    - Atkins, Sally (Box 3)
    - Atwood, Calvin (Box 3)
    - de Avalle-Arce, Diane (Box 3)
    - Banks, Josephine (Box 3)
    - Barbee, Pam (Box 3)
    - Barbee, Paul (Box 3)
    - Barbee, Paul A., (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Basket, Warren H. (Box 3)
    - Bazankov, Mikhail (Box 3)
    - Beach, John, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Behrangi, Samad (Box 3)
    - Benz, Maudy L. (Box 3)
    - Berkley, Richard E. (Box 3)
    - Bigham, K. (Box 3)
    - Bisbout (?), Allan (Box 3)
    - Blalock, Sally (Box 3)
    - Blalock, Debbie (Box 3)
    - Blanton, Kathryn (Box 3)
    - Bodenheimer, Ted, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Bolton, Betty (Box 3)
    - Bragg, Linda Brown (Box 3)
    - Broili, Susan, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Brook, James (Box 3)
    - Brooks, Ann (Box 3)
    - Brooks, James (Box 3)
    - Brothers, Mae N. (Box 3)
    - Bruchac, Joseph (Box 3)
    - Brunazzi, Elizabeth (Box 3)
    - Bullock, Jonah (Box 3)
    - Bullock, Lily (Box 3)
    - Burleson, Bob (Box 3)
    - Burns, S.S. (Box 3)
    - Burns, Stanley (Box 3)
    - Cambanis, Miranda (Box 3)
    - Can, Jason (Box 3)
    - Carl, Rev. William J. (Box 3)
    - Carlton, Amber Alice (Box 3)
    - Casper, Morris (Box 3)
    - Cassidy, Olive (Box 3)
    - Cates, Garth (Box 3)
    - Chambers, Etta Dickey (Box 3)
    - Chambers, Percy (Box 3)
    - Clay, Marianne (Box 3)
    - Cody, James (Box 3)
    - Cole, Vida B. (Box 3)
    - Cole, Vida B. Howard (Box 3)
    - Corseri, Gary (Box 3)
    - Cox, Elizabeth Barks (Box 3)
    - Creed, Lisa (Box 3)
    - Cutuly, Joan (Box 3)
    - Davenport, Doris (Box 3)
    - Davenport, Doris Juanita (Box 3)
    - Davis, Alice Woosley (Box 3)
    - Day, Ella (Box 3)
    - Day, Jim (Box 3)
    - del Vecchio, Gloria (Box 3)
    - Dempsey, Ivy (Box 3)
    - Dorset, Gerald (Box 3)
    - Eakins, Patricia (Box 3)
    - Eckblad, John P. (Box 3)
    - Edelson, M. and B. (Box 3)
    - Edwards, Wilton Henry (Box 3)
    - Eichenberger, Cecilia (Box 3)
    - Eisenstein, Abraham (Box 3)
    - Erhardt, Jean D. (Box 3)
    - Eubanks, Georgann (Box 3)
    - Fields, Needham (Box 3)
    - Fletcher, Suzanne, M.D. (Box 3)
    - Foreman, Paul, (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - Fowler, Gene, (6 folders) (Box 3)
    - Fox, Kirsten (Box 3)
    - Foy, Elbert A. (Box 3)
    - Frederick, Joseph (Box 3)
    - Freeman, Connie, (11 folders) (Box 3)
    - Frisher, Deborah (Box 3)
    - Gafford, Charlotte (Box 3)
    - Gainor, Sam (Box 3)
    - Gayatri (Box 3)
    - Gilbo, Anna Carolyn (Box 3)
    - Gleason, Mara (Box 3)
    - Golden, Gail Kadison (Box 3)
    - Goolsby, Elaine L. (Box 3)
    - Goolsby, Elaine L. and Graham G. Campbell (Box 3)
    - Goolsby, Elaine and Graham Campbell, (5 folders) (Box 4)
    - Gowen, Claire (Box 4)
    - Graham, Janie (Box 4)
    - Graham, Ronald (Box 4)
    - Green, Jaki Shelton, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Greer, Sylvia (Box 4)
    - Gretz, Margaret Hirschberg (Box 4)
    - Hagan, Kay (Box 4)
    - Hammond, Karla M. (Box 4)
    - Harlan, Terrie (Box 4)
    - Harlee, John (Box 4)
    - Harris, Louise (Box 4)
    - Hatley, Mary A. (Box 4)
    - Hauptman, Robert (Box 4)
    - Head, Thomas (Box 4)
    - Henderson, Ruby (Box 4)
    - Henderson, Shaun O. (Box 4)
    - Herron, Bill, (4 folders) (Box 4)
    - Hines, Phil (Box 4)
    - Hobson, Pete (Box 4)
    - Hobson, Shirley (Box 4)
    - Holman, John (Box 4)
    - Holt, Rochelle (Box 4)
    - Homsley, Bonnie Sue (Box 4)
    - Howard, Donna B. (Box 4)
    - Huey, Tom, (6 folders) (Box 4)
    - Hughes, Donna M. (Box 4)
    - Huls, Robert (Box 4)
    - Hunt, Nan (Box 4)
    - Inez, Colette (Box 4)
    - Ingram, Elwanda D. (Box 4)
    - Jamir, S. (Box 4)
    - Jamir, Sally (Box 4)
    - Jenkins, Athena (Box 4)
    - Jerry, Bernie C. (Box 4)
    - Johnson, Curt, (5 folders) (Box 5)
    - Johnson, H. Eugene (Box 5)
    - Johnson, Paulette S. (Box 5)
    - Jones, Johnston, Ellen (Box 5)
    - Jones, Brenda V. (Box 5)
    - Jones, John L. (Box 5)
    - Jones, Joyce (Box 5)
    - Kamoroff, Bernard (Box 5)
    - Kelso, Elizabeth Devereux (Box 5)
    - Kamau, Akua (Box 5)
    - Kilby, P. (Box 5)
    - Killian, Dorothy Jean (Box 5)
    - Kiztner, Diane (Box 5)
    - Knoop, Jennie (Box 5)
    - Knowles, Carrie, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Knowles, Carrie J. (Box 5)
    - Knox, Idris K. (Box 5)
    - Knox, Julie Johnson (Box 5)
    - Koestenbaum, Phyllis (Box 5)
    - Koons, Cedar (Box 5)
    - Kratt, Mary (Box 5)
    - Kratt, Mary Norton (Box 5)
    - Krok, Peter (Box 5)
    - Kurtin (?), Curt G. (Box 5)
    - LaBarthe, Penelope Dee (Box 5)
    - Laska, P.J. (Box 5)
    - Laurie (?), Ron (Box 5)
    - Leard, Lonnie (Box 5)
    - Ledbetter, Janice (Box 5)
    - Lenzer, Jean (Box 5)
    - Leroe, Ellen (Box 5)
    - Levy, Roger (Box 5)
    - Lewis, Jo Ann (Box 5)
    - Lignell, Kathleen (Box 5)
    - Lincoln, C. Eric, (4 folders) (Box 5)
    - Lindmark, Don (DAAL), (5 folders) (Box 5)
    - Liner, Amon, (8 folders) (Box 5)
    - Liner, Amon, (4 folders) (Box 6)
    - Lion, Maynard (Box 6)
    - Lockwood, Guy (Box 6)
    - Lomick, Joe B. (Box 6)
    - Lomick, Joe Bryant (Box 6)
    - London, Lisa (Box 6)
    - Lord, Gigi (Box 6)
    - Lyman, Mitchell Forrest (Box 6)
    - Magers, Steve (Box 6)
    - Maino, Jeannette (Box 6)
    - Maiz, B. F. (Box 6)
    - Manazar (Box 6)
    - Mariposa (Box 6)
    - Marsh, Henry W. and McGee, Elizabeth D. (Box 6)
    - Massaro, M.A. (Box 6)
    - Matijasic, Anna E. (Box 6)
    - Matthews, William, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - May, Gerald (Box 6)
    - Mayfield, Chris (Box 6)
    - McCleery, Nancy (Box 6)
    - McKnight, Jo-Anne (Box 6)
    - McLellan, Faith (Box 6)
    - McNamara, Marjorie (Box 6)
    - McNamara, Sally (Box 6)
    - Merritt, Rob, (3 folders) (Box 6)
    - Michael, Marilyn (Box 6)
    - Miles, Josephine (?) (Box 6)
    - Milosz, Czeslaw (Box 6)
    - Moorefield, Keith W. (Box 6)
    - Moorhead, Meggan (Box 6)
    - Morson-Baker, Sharlene, (5 folders) (Box 6)
    - Munn, Helen Clare (Box 6)
    - Murphy, Joy (Box 6)
    - Natkie, John L. (Box 6)
    - Navarre, J. Piirto, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Neeld, Judith (Box 6)
    - Neely, Barbara (Box 6)
    - Newman, P.B. (Box 6)
    - Nickerson, Sheila (Box 6)
    - Nickerson, Sheila B. (Box 6)
    - Niebauer, Abby (Box 6)
    - Odom, Dorothy S. (Box 6)
    - Odum, Dorothy (Box 6)
    - Olney W.W., (3 folders) (Box 6)
    - Orlock, Carol (Box 6)
    - Outlaw, Louise L. (Box 6)
    - Page, Donald L., (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Panaretou-Cambanis, Miranda (Box 6)
    - Paris, Cindy (Box 6)
    - Parker, Dorothy (Box 6)
    - Parker, Joseph (Box 6)
    - Pember, Cheryl A. (Box 6)
    - Pena, Jerry, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Phillips, Marion (Box 6)
    - Pocock, Christine (Box 6)
    - Poirier, Marsha (Box 6)
    - Pride, Anne (Box 6)
    - Priestley, Mary Ellen (Box 6)
    - Quackenbush, Jan (Box 6)
    - Ramirez, Sharon (Box 6)
    - Randolph, Leonard (Box 6)
    - Randolph, Leonard, (4 folders) (Box 7)
    - Ranson, Rebecca, (5 folders) (Box 7)
    - Reardon, Patrick (Box 7)
    - Reeder, Achsah (Box 7)
    - Reeder, Achsah J., (5 folders) (Box 7)
    - Reddy, T.J. (4) (Box 7)
    - Reivelson, Lisa (Box 7)
    - Reynolds, Oliver (Box 7)
    - Richardson, Carolyn, (3 folders) (Box 7)
    - Rigsby, Michael D. (Box 7)
    - Roadmap Students (Box 7)
    - Roberta (Box 7)
    - Robertson, Foster (Box 7)
    - Rodrian, S. Dan (Box 7)
    - Rogers, Gloree, (6 folders) (Box 7)
    - Rogers, Gloree, (4 folders) (Box 8)
    - Rose, Kate (Box 8)
    - Rudder, Virginia L., (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - Rush, Florence (Box 8)
    - Russell, Randee (Box 8)
    - Russell, Randee Yingling (Box 8)
    - Saleh, Lisa (Box 8)
    - Sax, Joel (Box 8)
    - Schange, Onaway (Box 8)
    - Schenck, Swan (Box 8)
    - Schier, Jacques (Box 8)
    - Seymour, Robert E. (Box 8)
    - Shelton, Jaki (Box 8)
    - Shelton, Sherman (Box 8)
    - Omawale (Box 8)
    - Shuman, Mark (Box 8)
    - Singer, Andrew (Box 8)
    - Smith, Dave (Box 8)
    - Smith, Karen S. (Box 8)
    - Smith, Richard J. (Box 8)
    - Sofinet, Varile (Box 8)
    - Southgate, Christopher, (10 folders) (Box 8)
    - Stephens, Margaret, (6 folders) (Box 8)
    - Spencer, Brent (Box 9)
    - Stanford Jr. High Students (Box 9)
    - Steiner, Claude (Box 9)
    - Stephenson, Shelby (Box 9)
    - Stevenson, John (Box 9)
    - Stevenson, William R. (Box 9)
    - Strongin, Lynn (Box 9)
    - Studer, Constance (Box 9)
    - Sun, C. H. (Box 9)
    - Swann, Carinda (Box 9)
    - Taylor, Helen Kressman (Box 9)
    - Thorpe, Earl E. (Box 9)
    - Timmerman, William (Box 9)
    - Trotter, William R. (Box 9)
    - Turner, Terry (Box 9)
    - Valtorta, Laura, (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Varner, Donna L. (Box 9)
    - Veach, Daniel (Box 9)
    - de Ventadorn, Bernart (Box 9)
    - Ward, Jerry W., Jr. (Box 9)
    - Watkins, Carolyn (Box 9)
    - Watson, Dakota (Box 9)
    - Weaver, Marvin (Box 9)
    - Wefing, Henry (Box 9)
    - Werden, Frieda (Box 9)
    - Weston, Anne (Box 9)
    - White, Emily (Box 9)
    - White, Gail (Box 9)
    - White, Morris G. (Box 9)
    - Whitebird, Joanie (Box 9)
    - Wiegers, Daniel B., (3 folders) (Box 9)
    - Wilson, Jean (Box 9)
    - Wilson, Richard (Box 9)
    - Woessner, Warren (Box 9)
    - Wolbarsht, Roz (Box 9)
    - Yensen, Kathy (Box 9)
    - Yergan, Leonore W. (Box 9)
    - Zabor, Doug (Box 9)
    - Zdanski, Celeste (Box 9)
    - Zimmer, Virginia (Box 9)
    - Zomparelli, Wendy (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous Authors (Box 9)
  - Publications Subseries, 1982-1990 and undated
    Books and pamphlets published by Carolina Wren Press.
    Arranged alphabetically.
    - Anthology: Eat Your Nachos (Box 9)
    - Anthology: A Living Culture in Durham, (4 folders) (Box 9)
    - Anthology: Thanksgiving Fun (Box 9)
    - Bombs, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Chrome Grass (Box 10)
    - Dr. Faustwitz, Spaceman, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - A Living Culture in Durham, (4 folders) (Box 10)
    - Plum Blossom, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - The Quiet Poems (Box 10)
    - Rainbow Roun Mah Shoulder, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Roadmap, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Roadmap (cont.) (Box 11)
    - This Road Since Freedom, (3 folders) (Box 11)
    - The Traffic of the Heart, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Watering the Roots of a Democracy, (5 folders) (Box 11)
  - Printed Material Subseries, ca. 1972-1985 and undated
    Chiefly material advertising publications, readings, small presses, and workshops; samples of volumes published by various small presses and sent to Judy Hogan; clippings regarding Carolina Wren Press or other small presses and their publications; and catalogs advertising the publications of small presses.
    Unarranged.
    - Printed material: General, ca. 1972-1985 and undated (Box 12)
    - Printed material: Small presses, ca 1975-1985 and undated (Box 13)
    - Printed material: Small press volumes, 1974-1981 (Box 14)
    - Printed material: Small press catalogs, 1975-1981 (Box 15)
    - Printed material: Clippings, 1970-1990 and undated (Box 16)
  - Lollipop Power Press, Series, ca. 1969-1986 and undated
    Correspondence, office files, financial papers, and publications of feminist children's press.
    Arranged only by type of material.
    - Correspondence and office files, ca. 1973-1986 and undated (Box 17-18)
    - Office files and financial papers, ca. 1973-1986 and undated (Box 19)
    - Financial papers, ca. 1972-1986 and undated (Box 20)
    - Financial papers and volumes, ca. 1970-1986 and undated (Box 21)
  - Homegrown Books Subseries, ca. 1972-1985 and undated
    Papers regarding Homegrown Books, an organization providing reviews of small press publications, and copies of reviews written by its members.
    - Homegrown Books Papers, 1972-1985 and undated (Box 22)
    - Homegrown Books Reviews and Reviews, 1972 -1985 and undated (Box 23)
    - Homegrown Books Reviews and Reviews, 1972 -1985 and undated (Box 24)
  - Hyperion Subseries, ca. 1966-1980 and undated
    Correspondence concerning the publication of Hyperion (poetry journal edited by Judy Hogan); manuscripts (some photocopies) of submissions to the journal; and issues of Hyperion
    Arranged only by category of material.
    - Business papers and writings, ca. 1966-1980 and undated (Box 25)
    - Volumes, 1969-1980 (Box 26)
  - Grant Material Subseries, ca. 1973-1980 and undated
    Expenditure reports and grant applications for Carolina Wren Press. Includes NEA Grants and grant material for the Durham Arts Council,the North Carlina Arts Council, and the North Carolina Humanities Commission.
    - Grant material: General (Box 27)
    - Durham Arts Council (Box 28)
    - NC Arts Council (Box 28)
    - NC Humanities Forum (Box 28)
  - Organizations Subseries, ca. 1973-1987 and undated
    Information regarding various organizations with which Judy Hogan and the Carolina Wren Press were involved.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of organization.
    - Afro-American Cultural Center (Box 29)
    - Black Writers' Group (Box 29)
    - Central American Projects (Box 29)
    - Coordinating Council of Literary Magazines (Box 29)
    - Durham Arts Council (Box 29)
    - Fellowship to Reverse the Arms Race (Box 29)
    - Kostroma Committee (Box 29)
    - NC Arts Council (Box 29)
    - NC Writers' Network (Box 29)
    - Outreach for Inmates (Box 29)
    - Poetry Council of NC (Box 29)
    - Prison Project (Box 29)
    - Rural Review Project (Box 29)
    - Unicorn Press (Box 29)
    - Women's Narrative Conference (Box 29)
  - Office Files Subseries, ca. 1979-1988 and undated
    Memos and notes concerning the operations of the Carolina Wren Press office. Includes mailing lists.
    Arranged alphabetically by subject and type of material.
    - Durham Anthology Orders (Box 30)
    - Lincoln Project (Box 30)
    - A Living Culture in Durham (Box 30)
    - Mailing Labels and Memberships (Box 30)
    - Mailing Lists and Phone Messages (Box 30)
    - Marathon Typography Service File (Box 30)
    - Meeting Minutes 1986 (Box 30)
    - Phone Logs (Box 30)
    - Resumes & Job Descriptions (Box 30)
    - University & Colleges Mailing Lists (Box 30)
  - Financial Papers Subseries, ca. 1973-1988 and undated
    Bills, accounts, bank statements and other miscellaneous financial records concerning the operations of Carolina Wren Press.
    - Financial Papers (Box 31-35)
  - COSMEP Subseries, 1970-1982 and undated
    Correspondence, flyers, agendas, and other material concerning the Committee of Small Magazine Editors and Publishers.
    - COSMEP papers (Box 36-37)
  - Photographs and Audiovisual Material Subseries, ca. 1950-1985 and undated
    Photographs of Judy Hogan and her family and friends, some of whom are affiliated with the Carolina Wren Press; tape recordings of symposia, lectures, and poetry readings by Judy Hogan and others; Oral History interviews of women in the Rougemont, NC Quilting Project; and videotapes of readings sponsored by the Carolina Wren Press and of the Donahue show on which Maya Angelou and Alice Walker were guests. Unarranged.
    - Photographs and audiovisual material (Box 38)
- Carolina Wren Press: Judy Hogan Papers Series
  - Correspondence Subseries, 1940-1993 and undated
    Correspondence between Judy Hogan and her family and friends. Some letters contain information regarding Carolina Wren Press and Judy Hogan's writing and publication activities.
    Arranged chronologically by month and year. Boxes 50 and 51 contain folders the author arranged by authors' names, some with manuscripts attached.
    - 1940-1969 Oct. (Box 39)
    - 1969 Nov.-1971 Sept. (Box 40)
    - 1971 Oct-1974 .Sept. (Box 41)
    - 1974 Oct.-1977 Apr. (Box 42)
    - 1977 May-1979 Dec. & undated (Box 43)
    - 1980 Jan.-1982 Nov. (Box 44)
    - 1982 Dec.-1985 June (Box 45)
    - 1985 July-1987 Aug. (Box 46)
    - 1987 Sept.-1990 June (Box 47)
    - 1990 July-1993 & undated (Box 48)
    - N.d. (Box 49)
    - Correspondence arranged alphabetically by name and topic (Box 50)
    - Correspondence with writings (Arranged alphabetically) (Box 51)
  - Diaries Subseries, 1940-1991
    Personal diaries kept by Judy Hogan. Most entries concern her friends, her family, and her writing.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - 1952-1969 May (and pre-1973 fragments) (Box 52)
    - 1973 Jan.-1975 June (Box 53)
    - 1975 July-1976 Dec. (Box 54)
    - 1976 Dec.-1978 Sept. (Box 55)
    - 1978 Sept. -1980 Feb. (Box 56)
    - 1980 Feb.-1981 Jan. (Box 57)
    - 1981 Jan.-1981 Dec. (Box 58)
    - 1981 Dec.-1982 Sept. (Box 59)
    - 1982 Sept.-1983 Apr. (Box 60)
    - 1983 Apr.-1983 Nov. (Box 61)
    - 1983 Nov.-1984 Aug. (Box 62)
    - 1984 Aug.-1985 Mar. (Box 63)
    - 1985 Mar.-1986 Jan. (Box 64)
    - 1986 Jan.-1986 Dec. (Box 65)
    - 1986 Dec.-1988 Feb. (Box 66)
    - 1988 Feb.-1989 Jan. (Box 67)
    - 1989 Jan.-1989 Dec. (Box 68)
    - 1989 Dec.-1990 Sept. (Box 69)
    - 1990 Dec.-1991 Dec. (Box 70)
    - 1991 Dec.-1992 Mar. (Box 71)
  - Writings Subseries, ca. 1970-1990 and undated
    Poetry, fiction, interviews, and essays written by Judy Hogan.
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - American Cultural Ritual Vivisection (Box 72)
    - Artemis and Poke (Box 72)
    - As Easily as the Sun (Box 72)
    - Bending the Sky (Box 72)
    - Besanded Castles, WomenWarriors (Box 72)
    - Black and White Together... We Shall Overcome Someday (Box 72)
    - Blooming Again (Box 72)
    - A Brief History and Description of the Carolina Wren Press (Box 72)
    - Carolina Wren Press, A Small Press "In Residence" In Durham (Box 72)
    - Carolina Wren Press: Writing Lives (Box 72)
    - Carpet Man (Box 72)
    - Cassandra Speaking (Box 72)
    - Charles Edward Eaton: A Poet Ripening Past Despair (Box 72)
    - A Christmas Fairy Book For Children (Box 72)
    - Chrome Grass (Preface) (Box 72)
    - The Condensing Poet (Box 72)
    - The Cry of Achilles: An Essay on Homer's Iliad (Box 72)
    - Doorways (Box 72)
    - Epic (Box 72)
    - Feel Free (Box 72)
    - Feign'd Deaths, (2 folders) (Box 72)
    - Feminization of Politics (Box 72)
    - Fiction by Curt Johnson (Box 72)
    - For Silence is Both (Box 72)
    - For Y(our) Freedom (Box 72)
    - For Y(our) Freedom--With Moyo (Box 72)
    - Going Alone (Box 72)
    - Gold Goldenrod, WhiteButterfly (Box 72)
    - He Grew Like the Summer Grass (Box 72)
    - High-Spirited Workhorses: An Essay on Russian Women (Box 72)
    - Homemade Bread (Box 72)
    - How Do I See Myself as a Mother Leader (Box 72)
    - Idea-Fish: The Use of Metaphor in Writing Poetry (Box 72)
    - The Interpretation of Literature and Bergson's Ideas (Box 72)
    - Julia and Mr. Jones, Meet the Master (Box 72)
    - The Kanga-Roo Weekly News, (4 folders) (Box 72)
    - Ladies Around the Crafts Table (Box 72)
    - Leadership (Box 72)
    - Let's Get the Van on the Road (Box 72)
    - Letter in a Bottle (Preface) (Box 72)
    - Light, break (Box 72)
    - Light - Sensitive (Box 72)
    - Light - Food (Box 72)